RYAN P. HICKEY

3233 Broadmoor, Fairfield, CA 94534 • (707)-580-9817

Portfolio: https://ryanpjhickey.github.io/portfolio/

Email: ryanpjhickey@gmail.com • GitHub: https://github.com/ryanpjhickey/

Objective

I am interested in pursuing a full-time opportunity in entry level software engineering roles. I am flexible and adapt to change quickly. I have successfully worked in remote environments to earn my degree and deliver results in my current role. I regularly engage with diverse groups and value being a part of a team that builds relationships and trust to achieve our goals.

Technical Skills

• Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Git/GitHub, Bootstrap, Bulma, Node.js, React.js, Jest.js, SQL, MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Handlebars.js, GraphQL, Apollo, Java, VBA, Replit, and C#.

Projects

Cook-Book | https://github.com/ryanpjhickey/cook-book

- Cook-Book is a blogging site that helps to connect people who are interested in cooking, creating, and sharing recipes. Users can add friends, as well as upload, share, and save recipes.
- Built using React.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Apollo, GraphQL, Node.js, Heroku, and Axios.

Paws-to-Home | https://github.com/ryanpjhickey/Paws-to-Home

• Paws-To-Home is a web page that helps to connect people with cats and/or dogs they are interested in adopting. Users can search for cats & dogs by location and or age. • Built using HTML, CSS (Bulma), JavaScript, and jQuery.

Java Banking App | https://github.com/ryanpjhickey/banking-app

• Simple banking app that utilizes a menu interface that allows users to create an account, transfer money, view their balance, as well as log in and log out of their account. • Built using Java and MySQL.

Education

U.C. Davis Continuing and Professional Education Bootcamp Certificate Graduated with a 93% from U.C. Davis's 24-week intensive coding bootcamp program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Bulma, Node.js, React.js, Git/GitHub, Jest.js, SQL, MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Handlebars.js, GraphQL, and Apollo.

California State University of Sacramento

B.A. in Communications and Media Studies, December 2020, 3.3 GPA

Experience

Marsh McLennan Agency - Insurance Associate

August 2021 - Current

- · Promoted from Insurance Trainee to Insurance Associate in 6 months · Developed and implemented automation of Excel processes using VBA · Assisted with testing and implementation of new software systems to improve efficiency · Process certificates of insurance for clients in a timely manner
- · Organize files electronically to support customer service team
- · Provide customer service to clients via phone, email and in person visits · Regularly assigned to team member's desks during PTO and medical leave

HMS Law Group, LLP. – File Clerk

February 2020 - March 2021

- · Recruited by Professor Rebecca A. Gardner to interview for a part-time position at HMS
- · Organize files physically and electronically to assist lawyers
- · Update and maintain online filing systems
- \cdot Manage daily visits to state buildings to safely deliver legal documents \cdot

Provide customer service to clients via phone, email and in person visits ·

Retained to work remotely during Covid

· Transitioned to a full time position post-graduation

California State University of Sacramento, Linguistics Research Assistant

April 2019 – August 2019

- · Recruited by Professor Xianghua Wu to assist on a fully funded linguistics research study
- · Recruited research participants and scheduled times for testing
- · Explained parameters of study to participants to ensure clarity and success
- · Updated Excel documents to establish clarity between documents and established templates for consistent recording of data

Additional Skills

• Successfully collaborated with diverse groups in remote environments to deliver results • Proficient in Mandarin as a result of elective studies and extended visit to China in 2018 • Proficient in Excel and VBA, utilized critical thinking skills and research skills to optimize efficiency